- I
Speaker 1: want to share with you a personal story.
One of my
Speaker 1: biggest dreams was to visit Miami because in 1968, when I was born, most of my father's family left Cuba, so I have never met them. And,
Speaker 1: Due to the new times, we've got visas for a complete family to come to US for the first time last year. I am so proud either because I had my own resources to do this family trip, so I could introduce my 10-year-old daughter to my family here.
I
Speaker 1: cannot tell you enough how important it has been to be a real family again. If you ask my daughter, when she hears talking about distance and walls, she doesn't understand. For her, everything seems like unreal.
Speaker 1: And I wish that could be true. I wish that the next president, I mean the president-elect in the US, Donald Trump, will not change the policy toward Cuba. We want to continue the relationship. We have so much in common.
I
Speaker 1: truly believe that we need to work together to build a new bright future, trust me.
So, the
Speaker 2 (higher-pitched voice): changes made by the U.S., such as increasing flights, increasing travelers to Cuba, facilitating commerce,
this has
Speaker 2 (higher-pitched voice): been important because it has made our business grow.
Speaker 2 (higher-pitched voice): So, this is such an important moment for Cubans. We are worried about the future. And that's why we're here today representing our businesses, representing the rest of the Cuban entrepreneurs and all of our families, because our families depend on these changes and this relationship moving forward. So, our message is that we want the U.S.-Cuba relationship to continue.
No
Speaker 2 (higher-pitched voice): nos den la espalda. Please, don't turn your
back on
Speaker 3 (higher-pitched voice): us. And I want to release a letter. This letter has been written for all of us. It has been signed for me and for, well, three beautiful women and entrepreneurs also.
Speaker 3 (higher-pitched voice): and for over 100 cuentapropistas,
Speaker 4: that's what we call the entrepreneurs
in Cuba.
Speaker 3 (higher-pitched voice): Here we ask President-elect Donald
Trump to
Speaker 3 (higher-pitched voice): continue the relations with our country, to build the progress, and also to invite him to come to Cuba and see the growth there, all the private business,
Speaker 4: and to see how this relation has been good for us. Thank
you.